Jarrell Houston

Web Developer

Fort Worth, TX 76106

<u>Jhouston2882@gmail.com</u>

<u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jarrell-houston-9857b210a/</u>
773-726-3739

Passionate and highly skilled web developer with 2+ years of experience developing and maintaining web applications. Strong skills in front end development along with sufficient knowledge of backend with the determination to become a full stack developer. Looking to apply my skills to a company that has growth potential and share knowledge with fellow coders.

Portfolio

Website: http://www.jhouwebdev.com

Github

http://www.github.com/Jarrell28

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

• Frontend: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Jquery, Bootstrap, SCSS, ReactJS/Redux

Backend: PHP, MySQL, Laravel, Slim, Twig

Content Management Systems: Wordpress, craftCMS

• Version Control: Git, Github

• Design: Photoshop

Work Experience

Front End Web Developer - Belniak Media - 10/25/2018 - 06/01/2019

- Developed websites from scratch using HTML, CSS, JS, and PHP for new clients.
- Implemented new features and updates to client's existing websites.
- Converted static websites into editable and reusable templates in craftCMS.
- Interacted with database using PHP to display dynamic data.
- Built contact forms using PHPMailer with Google Recaptcha.
- Built HTML emails and setup email templates in MailChimp.

MHA - United States Postal Service - 07/01/2018 - 10/11/2018

- Sorted mail to correct containers to be prepped for delivery.
- Loaded trucks according to schedule to meet delivery deadlines.

Operation Specialist - United States Navy - 03/29/2012 - 02/28/2016

- Operation Specialist in the United States Navy for 4 years in Sasebo, Japan.
- Worked on radar surveillance as Lead Air Tracker.
- Conducted training to lower ranking personnel.
- Maintained equipment and performed regular maintenance.

Education

Devry University - 01/03/2016 - 04/01/2018

Went to school for a bachelor degree in electronic engineering while working part-time

Simeon Career Academy

High school Diploma